Hey, it's 6:00
and the July 6th
uh meeting of the Cheyenne City Planning
Commission is now in order. Will staff
please call roll.
Daryl Hibbons.
Justin Trip
>> here.
Tony Lair
Bob Mia
>> here.
>> Megan Connor.
Amy Hernandez
>> presu
Wigum present. Mr. Chair, we do have a
quorum.
>> Okay. Thank you. Are there any
modifications to the agenda that we need
to deal with before proceeding?
Hearing none.
Uh,
can I have a motion on approval of
minutes for the May 18th meeting?
>> Commissioner Larrett.
>> Sorry, Mr. Chair. I I have a conflict of
interest if you want to back up to that.
>> Um, on my agenda that comes next.
>> I'm sorry. I'm looking ahead. Never
mind. I move to approve the minutes of
the May 18th, 2026 meeting. Okay,
>> it's been moved. Second. Do I have a
second?
>> Second.
Okay, it's been moved and seconded. Are
there any revisions, adjustments,
amendments to the the minutes as
drafted?
Hearing none.
Uh, all in favor of approval of the
minutes say I think we get to do this by
voice. Please say I.
>> I.
>> I. I.
>> Opposed? Say nay.
Okay,
that motion passes.
Can I have a motion on the minutes for
the June 1st, 2026 meeting?
>> So moved.
>> Second.
>> Okay, I'll take that as a a motion to
approve. Okay, it's been moved and
seconded. Any comments, adjustments,
amendments,
corrections
to the June 1st minutes? Hearing
none. All in favor of approval of the
June 1st meeting minutes, please say I.
>> I.
>> Opposed? Nay.
>> That motion carries.
Item three, disclosures, conflicts of
interest, etc.
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Commissioner Lair,
>> I uh I considered if I had a conflict of
interest, but decided I did not. But
I'll tell you what it was about. Uh just
like at the June 1st meeting. Um my son
does work for Microsoft. He's not
involved in uh planning or design of
future data centers. So I don't believe
that constitutes a conflict for me. In
any case, he does work at the data
center that uh campus that this proposed
one on our first item is about, but he
doesn't have anything to do with it
until it's in operation.
Okay. Thank you. Any other disclosures,
conflicts, exparte communications
hearing? None.
Will staff please read item A into the
record?
Item A, PDC-26-124,
North Range Business Park, 15 filing
assigned zoning.
>> I go first
here. Will the applicant?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. This is a signed zoning. Will
staff please read the staff report under
the record.
Chair and members of the commission
counterweight planning and development
department. The item before you it is an
assigned zoning. Um so that means this
goes with an annexation.
Um for this property uh
it is roughly 34.46
acres of land uh proposed to be annexed.
It is west of Round Top Road, south of
HappyJack Road. is right right next to
Here we go. It's right next to Northr
Range Business Park.
Zoning in the area um consists of the
county LU zoning to the west. You have
the BP zoning to the south and to the
east. And then there's a slight a tiny
little bit of AG um that's right there
to the north. Um
should there's a couple things I do want
to note with this project. On the
June 22nd city council meeting, they did
actually approve an outside water user
agreement for this property already um
with the assumption that it would be
annexed uh soon after. And that is
because it has an approved county site
plan for the parcel already. And that
county site plan is for
uh staging area uh that has parking and
office trailers uh for the construction
of the existing data centers. So the
parcel itself is not proposed for data
center development. It is already has
approval in the county for a staging
area. So it already has a site plan
approved already has development I
believe started on the property as well.
That's why they got the water the
outside water um agreement through
council is so that they can hook those
trailers to the water already uh prior
to annexation.
So staff reviewed this based on existing
zoning that surrounds the parcel uh and
having north range there the approved
industrial use from the county already
approved for the parcel. staff is
actually uh recommending that uh this
parcel be assigned the BP zone uh rather
than have it go through an a zone and
then into some sort of industrial zone
because it already has an industrial use
on it. It's also adjacent to the BP zone
as mentioned. the a use that is to the
north. Um that was done under our
original assigned zoning back when we
took what the uh underlying county zone
was and just gave it that which at the
time that parcel which is a Black Hills
substation
uh was zoned basically a in the county
is I think A1 or A2. Uh so that's how
that became agg.
Otherwise based on the review criteria
um and the surrounding zoning the
current use of the land staff recommends
uh the BP zone for this parcel and I do
stand for any questions.
>> Okay, I've got a question. Looking at
the staff report, uh kind of the cover
page indicates that the current zoning
is county LI,
not county LU.
>> Um even though in the memo later on it
refers to a county LU.
And just to complicate things further, I
go to our uh county assessors website
that and and and pull up the zoning and
maybe I'm not properly oriented cuz
looks like this butts
is adjacent to HappyJack Road to the
north. It looks like there is a county
alli zone out there.
>> So Mr. share through you. Uh, it is
accurate. It's all county LU.
>> So, but that was looks like I have a
typo in my staff report. Instead of a U,
I have an I, but it is county LU. So
land use.
Okay, I see where I'm reading the map
wrong. It looks like Okay.
Any other questions of staff?
Any questions from Zoom land?
I guess I've got another question.
Before the county did its wholesale
reszoning,
do we know what the prior zone was
before it became the generic land use?
>> Mr. chair through you.
I believe out here it probably would
have been a probably county A1 or A2.
Okay.
Put a pin in that. I'm just thinking
about our normal process and
I would like to little I think everybody
would want to know why a little more
about why we don't stick with the a
zoning
>> and Mr. Chair I'd like to add to the
future land use map for this area is all
mixeduse employment.
>> Okay, that's helpful. So even even if
the land was still a the whole area
that's right here is mixeduse employment
and based on even its adjacent zone
districts it and the current use of the
land being industrial. It fits better as
just giving it an industrial style zone
district upon annexation that would
allow it to continue operating as a
permitted use.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Is there any member of the public here
that would like to comment on this?
Uh
>> yes, [clears throat]
chairman, uh planning commission
members, Brad Emmens, maybe I think
Boyd, you kind of went through some of
the stuff that I was going to add to to
Connor's, uh report. I believe you can
kind of see I think it was A2. You can
kind of see it under the red crosshatch
there. that was the original county
zoning out here because those are the
largest sized lots and they were in the
old county. Um, this is one of those
times that the new county land use
designation and everything being a
conditional use permit is a little
strange because they kind of have
wrapped everything into a different
process. And so, um, it does have a
conditional use for the layown yard. Uh
this was split off just recently for
this purpose of being annexed and
brought into the city. I think the
county planning process finished
the um end of June. So um this went did
go through the county process to split
this parcel off and plat it separately.
Um, it is, I believe, even though Black
Hills owns both of those parcels, they
do own them in two different, so it's
basically two substations, one that's
zoned LI and one that's zoned AG uh, to
the north. So, I believe there's LI and
AG there. And then recently when the
city uh, annexed the North Range
Business Park, that's when the BP zoning
took over the rest of those those lots
that have business lots on them. So, um,
happy to answer any other questions.
I guess I should say we do agree with
the assigned zoning of BP.
Thank you. Are there any other members
of the public here to comment on this
item?
Public comment going once, going twice,
or is there anybody on Zoomland?
Yep.
public com we should probably have an
announcement for the folks on Zoom that
if they had intend to comment they need
to raise their hand before we close
public comment
for those members online if you do have
public comment please go ahead and raise
your hand
>> okay well thank you with that public
comment is now closed
commissioners Do I have a motion?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Leair,
>> I move to recommend the governing body
approve the assigned zoning for land
west of Roundtop Road and south of
HappyJack Road to BP Business Park as
shown in the attached zone change map,
noting that the project meets the review
criteria for approval.
Got
>> a motion. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
Thank you.
Got our properly moved and seconded
motion. Are there any comments,
discussion, any proposed amendments?
>> Hearing none. Will staff please call
roll.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Justin Trip.
No.
>> Bob Mati.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. Staff, please read on item B
into the record.
Item B, PUDC-26-126
A A and H park at Sweetgrass Expedited
Plat.
Let me go ahead. Our applicant is
online.
Applicant
Jacy, can you please
>> Good afternoon, chairman, members of the
planning commission.
Um, I appreciate you taking the time
this evening. Uh, the item before you is
has been a long time coming. um in the
Sweetg Grass annexation agreement and
subsequent PUD documents uh community
park to serve all of South Cheyenne was
uh intended and required to be provided
along the edge of the subdivision. So,
uh, we've been working for years,
literally years, with, uh, XL Energy and
Black Hills, the corner of Murray Drive
and Avenue C or Loving Trail, uh, has a
a high pressure metering station there.
And we've also been working with parks,
as you may have seen the recent PUD
amendments going through. Um, so working
with the parks department to uh master
plan the dedicated and master plan the
area for the public park and carve out
the southern portion uh for for private
recreation. Um, and I think you know
that that's all been approved by the
governing body and we are excited to
kind of bring this plat forward to
create some of those surrounding
rightaway extensions. Um and and we've
got buyin from XL Energy to go ahead and
and reconfigure their parcel to allow
for uh those two roads to go through. So
huge uh step forward for the network and
for Sweetgrass and for development of
the park. So uh really excited to bring
this before you this evening. Uh
generally, you know, no major comments
on the plat with the exception of the
roadways. Um there's about a mile and a
half of roads surrounding the the three
open sides of this plat um or three and
a half. And uh so you know we there
there obviously with the recreational
uses and the city park um there are no
commercial lots or uh or residential
lots included in this subdivision. This
is just rights of way and open space
recreation parcels.
So, um,
and and the reason I kind of bring that
up and and call it out is because the,
you know, the condition to, uh, create a
plan prior to recording the plat, um, is
totally acceptable. We understand the
need to kind of define and figure out
how these roads are going to be
constructed. Um there are sort of
development actions forthcoming uh on
three of the sides of this plat. Um and
the idea with this plat itself is just
to like I said create those rightaway
extensions that are hugely needed for
the network and and good for sweetgrass.
Um but there's no mechanism in place for
funding those. So we will continue to
work with staff uh engineering
and and the other um no on creating
those rights of way extensions to um you
know to to better the network but
there's no mechanism to be able to fund
those constructions with this plat and
like I said we have been working with
parks on the timing of that dedication
um that works best for them and um I I
think it would be benefit everybody
everybody including the city and
including the residents of South
Cheyenne if we could record the plat to
create the parcels and the rights of way
um potentially prior to having to sort
of bond for that uh those roadway
extensions. Um I feel pretty confident
that we can we can work out anou or
development agreement with the city um
you know pretty expeditiously but having
the condition be tied to recordation is
problematic. So I in my mind and and in
talking with SweetGrass, my client, uh
we would prefer that that be maybe tied
to a building permit or development
action. Uh just to allow us one the time
to to put that together and two the
ability to have some other development
action tied to it that would have
revenue. Um and I would mention that the
the entirety of the the platted lots in
the subdivision um are not for sale. So
the the 45 acres on the north end will
be dedicated donated you know free to
the city free of charge as part of the
open space for sweetgrass and then the
southern portion uh which is a little
under 30 acres will be donated to a
private recreation developer. Uh should
that not occur um or or if that does
occur either way if that land is
developed then there will be a
requirement to to build some of those
adjacent rights away. Obviously,
utilities extensions are another big
expense that's not mentioned in the
staff report. So, uh I apologize for
being a bit long-winded, but we would
hope that um we could tie that condition
number two uh to prior to further
development action as opposed to prior
to recordation. Uh if we record the plat
that would create the two parcels that
are proposed to be donated and that's
pretty important to both the private
recreation developer and the city of
Cheyenne parks department uh to be able
to have those be sailable or you know
giftable parcels. Uh so uh with that I'd
be happy to take any questions. Other
than that we agree with everything in
the staff report um and the and the idea
that there there has to be a plan there
has to be a development agreement. It's
just the timing of it that's a little
bit problematic.
>> Okay. Thank you. Before I turn it over
to anybody else, could you please flesh
out the phrase private recreation
developer a little bit so we have an
idea what we're talking about because I
was trying to figure out why we needed
two lots.
>> Yes. Thank you, chair. Um and I I did
want to mention also that um I I wanted
to apologize for being remote. I'd hoped
to be in person for this meeting but
wasn't able to make it. So, I appreciate
you hearing me virtually. Um I some of
you may have heard or or seen in other
um other actions like the PUD amendment
that there is a large indoor recreation
center private developer uh who's built
facilities elsewhere in the country and
is interested in building basically an
indoor fieldhouse. It would be a track
and field facility with some basketball
courts. uh and other recreation
facilities. And they they typically have
those that they'll people will travel
there with their team and train for a
week. So, it's kind of a sports retreat,
so to speak. And then they hold they
hold uh regional and national
tournaments in these facilities. and
they think that, you know, all the
number as far as they they're not my
client, but as far as I understand from
what they've told me, um they've kind of
got the whole deal put together, but a
big lynch pin in that is having the land
uh for the project. And so, uh
Sweetgrass has has offered to um to to
donate that land to their project so
that they can they can bring this
fieldhouse to Cheyenne. So that's um
that's what the south half of the parcel
is designated for. Uh it's in a
recreation zone in the PUD. So if that
deal fell through for any reason, it
doesn't uh doesn't kind of automatically
become something else. There is a
provision in the PUD that could be
developed for residential, but there's a
couple steps that would have to happen
for that to take place. So the intent is
for the entirety of the plat to be
recreational uses. Um the northern 45
acres would be a public city park and I
we we've been working with parks on on
getting a master plan put together for
that. Uh there will be a a full public
process just like any other parks master
plan.
>> Hey, thank you. Does anybody else have
any questions for the applicant?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> uh I think uh Commissioner Ma, you were
moving first. I was just wondering um
does the applicant know anything about
the funding that the parks has that will
be able to take care of this new
enlarged park?
>> Um chair through you. Uh that's a good
question. I think there are some funds
available. Uh, additionally, the uh,
sweetgrass when it was created with the
annexation agreement, um, there's a
separate fee structure additional to the
standard fees for uh, for parks and
wreck development and for transportation
development. So, um, for the the parks
part, um, we've been in discussions
about what what they have money for, um,
as it is, you just part of the in any
development when you have a public park
requirement, right? there's some public
obligation there, but um I think there
we we have talked about some avenues and
the first there's definitely enough
funding right now to make sure that we
get the the master plan uh process which
is not inexpensive in and of itself uh
finished and then the actual development
of it. Um there's some there there will
be some funds remaining and then we're
looking at other additional avenues uh
both public and private to fund that.
Um, and to jump back a little bit to the
surrounding roads, that condition number
two. Um, like I mentioned, there are
some funds available, but not enough to
build a mile and a half of roads and
utilities. Uh, I did attend a meeting
this morning with WOT and leads and no
about uh sort of some of the regional
improvements that need to happen and and
Loving Trail and Avenue 2 came up. So
there may be it may be part of a larger
network improvement plan, but um all of
that is very preliminary. And so right
now I think the key is to uh you know be
able to create these parcels for the two
potential recreation developers. I mean
the one the city for sure and the the
other potential uh so that so that that
can move forward as we work through the
the funding strategies and the theou and
development agreements to to kind of go
full development on on the surrounding
roadways.
And Commissioner Lair, do you had a
question?
>> I do. Thank you. Uh, I'm just wondering
about the uh this East Nation Road at
the south end of the plat and the east
end of that where it meets Sweetg Grass
Drive isn't exactly aligned. It's offset
from the road that same road I guess on
the other side of Sweetg Grass Drive.
Can you address that?
>> I can. Uh so we've been working with um
SweetGrass and the development partner
on those parcels you see to the east. Uh
I think there's some reconfiguration
that needs to happen in that plat. So
there will be a forthcoming plat to
realign that road. Uh so it'll be it'll
connect. Um and we we have that prepared
and they have their development plans in
order. Um they're just not quite ready
to turn that in at this point. So, um,
the idea is that that'll be replplatted
to a line. Currently, that's all just
vacant prairie land.
>> Are there any other questions from the
commissioners who are attending via
Zoom?
>> Yes, this is uh Justin Trip.
>> Commissioner Trip,
>> chairman through I just had a question.
Do we know what type of industry is
going to come in that west side or
potentially what type of industry or
warehouse?
>> Uh chair through you. Um I we don't uh
we don't control the lands to the west.
I know there is a housing nonprofit
housing developer that was looking at
some of the land in that unplatted
triangle to the west of east east nation
road. So that would be extended through.
You can see the flood plane there on the
map. Um so that's a a challenging uh
challenging extension, but we are
working with them on on how to push east
east station through to uh connect with
the the west portion of that. But
there's no no warehouse or industrial
development here. It's just the two
residential or two recreational lots.
>> Thank trip. Is that adequate or do you
have further questions?
>> No, I'm fine. Thank you.
>> Okay.
Any other questions? I've got I've got a
another couple of questions, but
anything from other commissioners, I
assume
hearing none.
Casey, can you please talk to us a
little bit about what's going on with
lots five and six? I you know I
understand the
pressure station or whatever in lot
three but we've got these two odd
slivers to the to the west of Loving
Trail that are set out as pair of
separate lots
for those and why they're in of that
size.
>> Yeah, thank you chair. Um as you can see
on the preliminary plat map um there are
a lot of utilities there. Um so the
current that that sort of southerntherly
portion of Loving Trail next to lot six
um that lines up with with the Loving
Trail all the way down to Bison Business
Park. So um that was platted oh gosh
three or four years ago um with the BOPU
water and sewer extensions. And so we
we've aligned with that where these
pipelines are and that's part of why it
was shifted to the east from where it
would ideally be. Um as you can see when
you cross Artisian Road those
high-pressure pipelines uh break off to
the east uh kind of avoiding lot three
where that metering station for those
pipelines is. And so um so these
remainders are just kind of left over
there. Um there is a potential that one
or both of those could be absorbed into
the lands to the west. Uh in the in the
PED master plan, those are shown as as
kind of greenway open space parcels
where you could have a trail. Um there's
limited work you can do obviously on top
of those pipelines. So uh we'll have to
work carefully with those different
providers, utility providers to uh what
we can do there. But essentially it, you
know, they're they're kind of kind of
wasted land because you can't do much
with uh with those pipelines there. But
um there's, you know, potentially going
to be a greenway trail and some
landscaping in those parcels. Um and you
you can't put any houses there. You
can't develop it for any kind of, you
know, commercial use or anything.
I guess my concern was whether or not
there was just going to be additional
grass green space there and having
people trying to cross streets while
enjoying the park. But
>> yeah, chair, I appreciate that. I it it
just kind of is what it is. But I think
the idea, you know, that the ideally
they would be there would be a greenway
trail running through there with some
some level of landscaping so that they
could be used as a as a trail corridor
with connections across Loving at those
main intersections into the into the
park and recreational parcels.
That's part of why they're designated as
remainder lots on this plat because
they're they're not very usable uh with
all those pipelines under there. But we
do have uh you know we would hope to
develop them for for some sort of
regional trail corridor.
>> Okay. Okay. And I guess last question is
I'm curious whose right idea it was to
have both a nation way and a nation road
in the south part of Cheyenne going east
and west because I think this is where
we would address
nomenclature streets if I'm correct.
Uh chair I can't speak to that. Uh we we
only named it Nation Road because there
is such a thing as Nation Road and
Nation Way. But uh I think Nation Way is
spelled as all one word. So I don't know
if that helps or not.
>> Okay.
Any other questions the applicant before
we ask for the staff report?
Hearing none will staff please read your
present your report.
Chair members of the commission
counterweight planning and development
department.
The plat before you is an expedited
plat. So preliminary and final plat for
roughly 91.29
acres of land. Uh this is proposed
south of East College Drive and west of
Sweetrass Drive in the Sweetrass
subdivision.
On the future land use map, uh this area
is designated with open space and parks
and then it is for zoning. It is part of
the SweetGrass PUB so it does fall under
their own zoning requirements rather
than uh fully being within the UDC
with the plat. Um it is proposing six
lots. So there are two lots uh for
recreational development. There is a
green uh a greenway lot along uh the
extension of
that Carlson
Murray along Murray Road. Um and then
you do have two remainder lots to the
west along Loving Trail and then the
utility station
uh has its own lot as well.
with the proposed plat through staff's
review. Um the biggest kind of comment
that came up uh which the applicant did
note is
how the streets are going to be
developed. Um per the UDC the
expectation with any plat is that that
plat basically uh whoever plat whoever
creates the plat uh they're required to
build the streets. Uh so that is the
expectation. Um
that usually comes with a requirement
that either there be well there be a
plan and a bond in place or there be
some sort of development agreement on
how those streets are going to be
developed and how the utilities are
going to be developed uh for that area
that is platted.
Something else uh through staff's review
um and you'll notice that there is the
staff recommendation for the exception
is the block size.
Um that does come up from time to time
with this one specifically though
because it is uh for recreational uses.
There is the exemption for block size
because generally with recreational use,
you're probably going to have different
points where you might have an entrance
on Sweetgrass Drive and then there's
also an entrance onto Loving Trail on
the west. So, you do get that connection
that goes through. It is just not a
public street. Um,
so it does break that up.
This is part of um within this week SPD
it does call this out as being uh
recreational and park area um which is
what this plaid is basically for. Uh I
should also note that some planning
commissioners may have seen this
preliminary plat before. Um this was
actually a preliminary plat that did get
approved several years ago. Um
preliminary plats are generally only
good for I believe 2 years and then they
do have to come back through the
process. Uh the original preliminary
plat was done when it carved off the
small square on the eastern side uh that
was for a future fire station.
So that's when that preliminary plaque
was here before planning commission and
did get approved and then got approved
by council as well. Um so very similar
layout. The biggest changes I would say
with this one is that it is splitting
that park parcel and that is due to uh
the applicant going through planning
commission and city council and did get
approval for the sweet grass pud
amendment uh that basically does allow
this to happen to carve off that
southern parcel for a private
recreational development
but again it still is in the pud and as
the mentioned is still for recreational
purposes.
So through staff's review, uh there are
some technical corrections that still
need to be um be made, but those can be
um finalized prior to recording of the
plat.
And then um the exp the exception to
block size.
And then the other uh staff
recommendation that prior to recording
of the plat is that a plan for
installation of all necessary public and
private improvements be in place and
assured by bond or certified check or a
development agreement or a written legal
obligation um be approved by the city.
Um development agreement shall be
drafted by the applicant and reviewed
and agreed upon by the planning and
development director and the city
engineer.
we have that in there and we have it for
prior to recording of the plat
um
because that's generally we'd like to
have that plan prior to a plat being
recorded as the UDC does require that
with any plat there is there's this need
to have something in place once those
streets become public rights of way for
them to be developed.
Uh this was discussed with our city
engineering office. Um I actually had a
discussion with uh staff engineer Aaron
Gates about how to craft this language
and this is what we had agreed upon um
as well as discussing this within the
planning and development department as
well.
So with that staff does recommend
approval with the exception in the two
conditions. And with that I am available
for any questions.
Has
there been any conversation
about what some kind of an agreement
would look like with city city attorney
chair through you? This has not been
discussed with the city attorney. Um the
city attorney gets involved once there
is any agreement drafted and prior to it
going to city council for actual um
adoption.
Has
there been any discussion of of
some sort of a development agreement
within the city that could meet the the
applicant's request that the triggering
mechanism occur when there's a
development action?
Is that something that
And I I hate to negotiate through here,
but I'm also thinking
I was frustrated when when this was
proposed as a park donation and and
instead the city decided to
just put on a ballot, spend a million
dollars to buy what is now Kowanas Park
when this was sitting here available and
the need for a park over here. And now
we're looking at park development. we're
trying to say, well, how can we
frontload the pro, you know, shift the
process and and and it's always annoyed
me that that we've not pounced on this.
So,
I'm looking for a motion to approve or
not. It sounds to me like the gap is
does somebody have to pay for the road
before
a donation for a park is there versus
let's just promise a million dollars and
then negotiate
chair members of the planning commission
Charles Bloom playing development
director perhaps an alternative way
forward would be to just have a blanket
recommendation that the roadway security
instrument be evaluated with city
council consideration because um
ultimately that will allow them to make
that final recommendation with their
approval and also the city engineer will
be present at that meeting who can um
discuss the nuances of either side of
things. But I think that might be a
better condition to be addressed at the
um governing body level
unless um Aaron Gates from engineering
wants to to chime in on that, but I'm
sure she would appreciate the latter
or the earlier, sorry, the earlier.
Um any other questions from the
commission for staff on this item?
Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Lar. Um, I'm still on that
same issue, but I'm but I'm thinking
back as I've heard a lot in the last
month or so because of the large
proposed annexation south of here, um,
about that when this land was annexed
with this proposed large residential
development, uh, there was I was
thinking they called it a development
agreement that was negotiated and
executed with a developer for the land
owner. Is that is that true? And I I
assume if it was, it didn't cover this
the details of this these particular
roads.
>> Chair through you. Uh so there was an
annexation agreement. Um yes, that has
come up at plenty of meetings. Um the
annexation agreement didn't do exactly
what everybody thinks it does. Uh they
didn't promise $15 million over five
years or anything like that. Um
what the annexation agreement did was
basically lay out a framework of how
Sweetgrass is going to develop. They
have a different kind of fee schedule
for park fees. They have an additional
fee that they put on themselves for
transportation
related um fees.
Uh it talked a little bit about the
donation of the park and things like
that. um all very standard things that
would have been required regardless of
the develop of the annexation agreement.
It did not speak about the roads
themselves and how they'd be developed.
uh I mostly spoke about the fact that
they can have slightly different road
variations than what the UDC calls out
or what standard road sections would
require uh for certain areas of
SweetGrass, but it did not specify how
exactly these roads would be developed.
And another one if I may. Um,
back to the East Nation Road.
Um,
so the the offset I mentioned and the
developer said that they'll clean that
up with the as they replat I guess the
the land to the east of that is just
kind of in draft form now. Is that is
that what I'm hearing? And is the
planning development department
comfortable with that?
uh chair through you. I'd have to defer
to our engineering office if they're
fine with how it's currently
offcentered. Um I do know with the
subdivision to
the
east, uh it is platted, does have a
final plat that is recorded. Uh no
utilities or roads are in place at this
time.
I was just thinking if if it would be
helpful to the cause, we we could uh
make a condition about that just to make
sure it's recognized as we move forward.
Our recommendation um but uh but another
part of that same thing I I also don't
I'm not real crazy about the name of the
road um being in conflict. Is this is
this how names get or roads get named? I
take it this road doesn't exist anywhere
else with this name. So this would be
the one time when it
>> share through you. So
>> saying it
>> we we do name uh roads with plats. Uh
this name does exist. It actually does
exist further to the west. You can kind
of see it on these maps. Um it just says
nation. Um but it is
nation road out there. It does exist. Um
this is just the other portion of it.
Uh but yes, when it comes to naming
roads, that happens at the platting
stage. We do actually sometimes have
conflicts and do require those to be
changed. Uh we have multiple agencies
that look at that. So we do have
emergency management looks at it, county
clerk's office looks at it, county
recording, everybody kind of takes a
look at the names of the roads to make
sure that they work. Um, with this there
were no no comments, no concerns uh with
the naming.
>> Is it is that other portion of the road
in the county? Is there any part of it
that's in the city?
>> Chair through you. Yes, the rest of the
road uh further to the west is in the
county.
>> So eventually as um Mr. Mr. Palma had
mentioned
>> the
basically this portion of East Nation
being platted will eventually connect
into the county portion further to the
west. So then you have a connection that
fully goes from Sweetgrass out towards
South Gley and then you'll have East
Murray to the north that also so you'll
have more points of entrance and exit
into Sweetgrass rather than the two
connections that they currently only
have along college.
Okay, thank you for that because that
was going to be my next question is
whether with uh various utility
easements whether there was going to be
able to be a connection or if we were
going to live in a world where East
Nation Road did not connect to East
Nation Road.
>> And Mr. Chair, um as the applicant
mentioned, uh there is the potential for
that triangle kind of portion that's
there to be developed. Um I can't say
what with at this time. We haven't had
anything
officially proposed. Um it could be
housing,
but then with that development, we would
require basically East Nation to connect
to Nation that's in the county so that
it extends also with this plat. Um it's
hard to see on the preliminary, but a
little bit better on the final, but
Artisian does have a connection into
Loving Trail as well with this plat. So
there is a small portion that would then
connect Artisian and the county to uh
Loving Trail. So then there is actually
I guess you could call it a third point.
It just doesn't go straight across cuz
you have the park, but it does create
another point.
I've got a one more question trying to
figure out how to solve for this issue
of sequencing. And I appreciate uh the
director's
uh comments. Um
would it be possible to advance this
without the East Nation Road designation
and and and cross that bridge when and
if there is a sale of the parcel to or
donation of the parcel to the
to the developer of the fieldhouse? I
guess this may be a question for
applicant as well, but I guess we're in
city council in in in city presentation
or is that not work? Mr. Chair, Seth
with the planning development
department. We need to select road names
with the plat. Um, you could recommend
that the council uh require the
applicant to change the name of the road
to a different name, but it would need
to be named going into recording.
>> Uh, that's not the question. And I'm
wondering about whether if if the hangup
is is a plat that has a road there if if
the road remains unplatted unless until
something happens that would cause the
need for that road like say a fieldhouse
or is am I way off base here?
>> Mr. Chair, with a platting action
adjacent to a major street on the major
street plan, we would expect that major
street to be platted. um nation is an a
major street on the major street plan.
So we'd expect this planning action to
dedicate at least half of the street. Um
because of the nature of the development
and the area, dedicating the full street
would be preferred.
Okay, thank you. That answers my
question. Are there any other questions
for city staff?
Is there any member of the public here
that wants to comment on this issue?
Seeing none, is there any member of the
public online that wants to comment on
this?
>> Okay, chair,
>> I just have the applicant's hand raised,
but not not a different member of the
public.
>> Okay. Would the applicant like to
respond to the non-existent public
comment before we close and proceed?
>> Mr. Chair, I appreciate your humoring me
on the public comment period. I I I
appreciate Mr. Mr. Bloom's suggestion. I
think the director uh is appropriate in
deferring that conversation to you know
we can we can have more discussions
internally. I also wanted to mention
that we can we can work with emergency
services and the GIS department on on
renaming the road. Um, so if if the
planning commission sees fit to uh move
the expedited plat forward uh with the
conditions as written, we're we're fine
with that.
>> Okay. And my view is doesn't make sense
to rename the road road if it's going to
connect with East Nation elsewhere. It
just seems like a bad idea from east to
west all the way across.
>> Yeah. Um,
so
before we close public comment and
how
if we're trying to bridge the gap
between committing public funds to or
committing private funds or a condition
to commit private funds to developing
the road before we allow the
plat to move forward and trying to defer
and stay within the UDC.
Can we please get some guidance on what
that might look like for those who might
make a motion
make
commission? Uh, Director Bloom, how we
if we were rewarding the condition,
would you please spoon feed that to us
as an alternative?
and chair, members of the planning
commission, I think it's okay to move
forward with it subject to staff's
recommendation and then at the end just
add something that says noting that the
planning commission requests further
discussion uh regarding the timing of
the development agreement related to uh
public and private improvements as
specified in condition two
by the governing body. I think that
something along those lines would work
and then applicant would that
help 2A specifically.
>> Yep. Chair through you. I I think that
is completely acceptable to us. Thank
you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
With that, I'm going to close public
comment and open this up for a motion
from the commission.
And I want to thank the developers of
Sweet Grass for continuing to press
forward with a park in this area.
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Lair,
>> I move to approve the A&H park at SweetG
Grass Preliminary Plat advancing the
final plat to the governing body. The
staff recommended exception and
conditions.
>> It's been moved. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Is there
any discussion, amendment,
etc. from the commission.
>> Mr. Chair, I'd like to
>> Yeah,
>> I'd like to propose the amendment that
director Bloom suggested earlier, though
I ran out of I'm not very fast at
writing down. So, he started off. So
adding on to the end of
2A I think the something like the words
noting that the planning commission
requests further discussion relating to
the timing of the and that's where I ran
past so I need to need some more help.
>> Commissioner believe please help of the
public and private improvements
that would be contained within the
development agreement.
And if you would like to add, you can
say specifically whether they should be
triggered to a building permit or
subdivision recording.
Sorry, plat recording. Like that better.
>> So contained within the what? What was
the next words there?
>> What were the previous words? Sorry.
Before contain.
>> Okay. So
further discussion relating to the
timing of the public and private
improvements that would be contained
within the
>> development agreement.
>> So my my uh preference would be to end
it there because I'm sure this same
discussion will be taking place with the
governing body and their committees. Um
so I don't know that we need to go into
any more details or or provide options
for them. That should be fine.
>> Okay, we have a motion to amend the made
motion. Is there a second to the motion
to amend?
>> Second.
>> Okay, it's been moved and seconded. Any
discussion on the amendment?
Hearing none, will staff please call
roll on the on Commissioner Leard's
amendment?
>> So, we're on the amendment.
Justin Trip,
>> yes.
>> Tony Lair,
>> I Mathia,
>> I.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. Now we're back on the
main motion as amended. Is there any
discussion
or further amendment to the motion
hearing? None. Will staff please call
rolling.
>> Tony Lair,
>> I.
>> Bob Mati
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Justin Trip.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
Okay. Thank you.
Other business staff amount
announcements.
>> Chair members of the planning
commission. You may have noticed that
with your minutes beginning on the the
meeting for June, we have changed the
format of our minutes. We used to do
verbatim minutes where we took extensive
notes of everything that happened. Um,
and there could be the opportunity for
error in there and they were very
timeconuming. We have now changed them
to action minutes which detail motions
that were made the motion maker and it
details folks that had public comment.
Um, it does meet the requirements for
minute taking. Um, and also we've gone a
little bit above because we've also
included links to all of the Zoom
meetings that have been recorded from
January 5th of this year onward and we
can plan to continue that. So within the
action minutes, you'll also note at the
end of every item there will be a
timestamp. Um, that is so if one wants
to know the exact discussion, they're
welcome to fast forward through the Zoom
video to get that specific item. Uh, you
all are our guinea pig right now. Um, so
you're the first board that we've
implemented this standard and we do
intend to move it to all of our planning
and development um, related boards. So
if you have any questions or concerns,
feel free to reach out to us, but uh,
pretty pretty snazzy we believe.
>> Thank you. Any other announcements
or other business,
>> Mr. Chair? uh counterweight planning
moment permit. There should be no midmon
July meeting. So enjoy frontier days,
enjoy July. Um won't have a meeting for
that for that meeting. Um
potentially there is no August meeting
for the first meeting of the month.
Potentially. I'm not going to guarantee
that yet because we haven't had our
submitt deadline which is this Wednesday
um for projects. So, the only thing that
we could see is potentially zone changes
um or
possibly other items, but right now,
first meeting of the month has no plat,
has no annexation, assigned zonings or
anything like that.
Um, later this week you should see
probably an email from me with a new
updated unified development code, the uh
entertainment district and all the
changes for the historic horse racing
did get adopted by the governing body.
So, I do have to make those changes. Um,
carports failed on second reading. So,
that didn't go anywhere. So, you won't
see that update. Um,
but the historic horse racing did get
adopted.
Other than that, I don't believe I have
any other announcements at this time.
>> Chair, members of the planning
commission, sorry, one more item
regarding the historic horse racing
changes. There was uh one change that
did occur through the council, the
governing body adoption process.
Initially there was a modification to
the performance uh standards for um in
relation to child care centers. Um two
things one thing had happened at the
planning commission level is it removed
the requirement that it only applied to
standalone centers and it applied to any
type of center like if it was in a
mixeduse um development if it was in a a
strip center those types of things.
Ultimately, that provision was deleted
from the uh development standards
section and it was included in a new
section 10 of the special use permit
approval process that basically said
that in the governing body making a
determination as to whether or not this
is appropriate um at a location, they
could evaluate his proximity to any
standalone child care center. Um, so
this was modified to be a review
criteria because there could be
geographic limitations or geographic
conditions that could limit access or
make it that it's not truly related. It
could be a creek, it could be a highway,
it could be a roadway. And then also
there was that fear of what would happen
if someone opened up a child care
specifically to make one non-conforming.
So it was changed to a review criteria
through the special use permit approval
process. So that was the one significant
amendment that was made through the
process between the planning commission
and the governing body.
Okay. Thank you. Any other business?
With that I guess I'm looking for a
motion to adjurnn
if one is required.
>> So move. Okay.
Believe we're adjourned.